所以今天早上我要跟大家分享的信息是神恩轉化的心心
神恩轉化的心心
有一次有一個機械工他在修理一個摩托車,把一個引擎蓋要拿掉的時候,看到有一個很有名的心臟科醫師
當這個心臟科醫師他事實上來是要找他們這裡面看看他自己的車子,這個時候這個機械工遠遠就向他來叫
要不要過來看看這個,那這個心臟科醫師有點驚奇,就過去到他那邊去了
那麼這個機械工他就把手擦了乾淨,過去跟這個醫生說,他說醫生你看看這個引擎,你看看我把他這個心打開了,把這裡面的所有東西修好了,把這個東西全部放好了以後,現在他像一個新的心
那到底怎麼回事呢,我一年才賺個差不多四萬塊錢,你好像賺了好幾百萬,這個到底是怎麼回事啊
那這個心臟科醫師就停下來,就想了一下,就過去跟這個機械工說,你試試看當引擎還在轉動的時候,你去做你的做的事情吧
當然要修復人的心,要比修這個汽車的這個引擎要難多了
那更難的呢,還不是這裡,更難的是什麼呢,是如果你要修復人的心,而且講的是一個樹林的心
這個修復人的心,只有神能夠做得到,只有靠著神的恩典能夠轉化人的心
當我們開始一個新的年,我們教會開始各種新的施工
我們這個時候,我們巴不得我們求神能夠轉化我們的心,讓我們跟我們的教會在這新的一年中間能夠有一個新的心
這就是神在聖經中間應許的
我們現在講的是英文跟中文翻譯,那我們大家一起來看
讀經的時候,現在要公平起見,我們只念粵語,因為今天講到的是有英文跟中文翻譯
我們大家一起來念
所以神在這個地方,他應許我們是要給我們一個新的靈,讓我們能夠怎麼樣去尊崇他
那麼第一點,我們要怎麼樣呢?我們要瞭解人心的實況
我們的心事實上是代表我們是誰的一個核心
就包括我們自己的價值觀,我們的觀念,我們的各方面的想法
以及我們的感受,我們的信仰,或者我們做出各種行為的一個前提的決定
這一個真實的狀況是,舊的心充滿了邪惡
耶和華看見人在地上的罪惡很大,終日心裡思念的盡都是惡
所以你在這段經文中,你認為人的心本質上是好的嗎?
如果你是這樣子思想的話,也許你並不了解我們人性的一個真實
你也許不知道什麼是一個真實的
聖經說人的心是充滿了邪惡
那麼也許你認為那只是發生在舊約的時代
那麼我們在羅馬書的第一章看看新約怎麼講
28,他們既然故意不認識上帝,上帝就任憑他們全邪癖的心行那些不合理的事
這講的是一個腐敗的心
所以人的心是充滿了各種各樣的一種邪惡的思念
聖經就是在這個地方,就是這樣子的來表達出人的心
所以這個並不是說這一個造物者的一個原來好的本意
在這種情況之下,人的心才有很多的不義,很多的邪惡
所以耶利米書第十七章這樣子說,人心比萬物都詭詐,壞到極處,誰能刺透呢?
所以這裡面說人心是壞到一個地步是別人沒有辦法刺透,甚至自己都不了解自己
Rick Warren的太太Kate,她第一次到盧旺達去訪問的時候,那年她五十七歲
因為她知道一九九四年在這個地方發生了一個種族滅絕,有一百萬個人被殺死
那麼這個裡面有很多人用很多酷刑讓他們死亡,那麼她說這種被害者我一來以後,我很容易就會看到誰是殺害者
她這個時候很天真的以為說我只要看到這些男男女女他們的眼睛,我就知道到底當初哪些人做了這些壞事
後來她說她其實在當初呢,她是滿心充滿了一個自義的一種論斷
那麼她所發現的到最後呢,讓她真的是不但是不知道怎麼樣來做決定,甚至她很害怕
那麼她看到的不是那些眼睛有邪惡的眼光的這些人,她所看到的事實上這些人就是跟我們一樣
他們這些人呢,就是去愛她的,跟她的靈色有很好的關係,去幫助人,甚至在教會裡面呢,他們一起敬拜
到底這些惡人呢,在哪裡?這些做很多壞事的人到底在哪裡呢?
慢慢地,在一種心裡面自覺的,但是讓自己很恐懼的過程,她才慢慢地找出來何謂真實
她說在盧萬達,沒有惡人,沒有這些怪獸,有的只是你跟我
因為我們當我們被放在這樣的一個場合的時候,我們都有能力,而且精於能夠用欺騙的方式來隱瞞我們自己的惡行
很可怕吧,但是確實是真實的,你現在了解了嗎?這就是人心,這就是為什麼我們需要耶穌
那我們的救星呢,同時也充滿了驕傲
在真言第十六章第五節,心裡驕傲的人,都是耶和華義務的,他們必不免受罰。這個地方講到的是人心的驕傲
在新約馬可福音第七章第22和23章,「偷盜、兇殺、姦淫、貪婪、邪惡、詭詐、淫蕩、窒盜、暴徒、驕傲、狂妄」
這裡面講到的是,我們所有的這些惡行,都是從我們裡面出來的
如果我們說嫉妒,是因為我們覺得每個人都比我好,因此我產生了一種憤恨
那麼驕傲就是我認為我總是比別人好的這種敗壞的心思
什麼是驕傲?驕傲就是把你的信心放在自己,而不是放在神的身上
所以聖經說,神不喜悅
那麼驕傲的核心就是自私
就是把自己放在首位
認為你是最重要的
認為你知道的最多
認為你配得的比別人應該更多
聽起來覺得很熟悉嗎?
驕傲是讓我們偏行己路,而不是行在神的道路
這個驕傲讓我們覺得我們不需要神,也不需要別人給我們的引導
這個驕傲事實上所有罪的根
驕傲會讓我們偏離神,而不是能夠轉向神
那麼一個人的不順服本身的一個根源就是驕傲
這種背後的背後也是驕傲
那麼對別人產生一些虐待的行為,本身也是因為覺得自己做所有的事情都是應該的
我們可以這個事情在家裡面
在我們各種關係上
在我們的社區裡面
甚至也發生在我們教會的一個家庭裡面
可怕,但是真的
你現在了解了嗎?
這就是為什麼我們需要耶穌,需要祂的幫助
舊的心還充滿了昏迷
你看看這張相片
以賽亞第四章第20節說
New Testament, Romans 1
因為他們雖然知道上帝卻不當作上帝榮耀他
也不感謝他,他們的思念變為虛妄
無知的心就昏暗了,自稱為聰明,反成了愚絕
The foolish hearts were darkened is become fools
Many studies have shown that people tend to exaggerate their positive characteristics and abilities
那麼很多的報告顯示我們一般人有這樣一個傾向
就是誇大自己好的那一面的品格
或者各方面的想法
For instance, studies have shown that most drivers think that they are better than average drivers
比如說開車的人研究說他開車開得比別人好
你是不是也這樣認為呢
Psychologists call this the state of illusory superiority, what a term
那麼心理學家稱這樣的一種想法是一種幻覺式的優越性
For example, in 2014, a team of British researchers tested this common
"better than average" tendency by surveying 85 convicts at a prison in England
那麼在2014年的時候有這些研究者呢
他們要證明這個所謂的我自己比別人好
他到監獄裡面去訪問了80幾位監獄的人
The inmates were aged 18 to 35
這都是18到35歲的罪犯
And the majority had been jailed for acts of violence or robbery
那麼這些人他之所以被關在監獄裡面呢是因為他有暴力或者有搶竊
The inmates completed questionnaires anonymously and in relative privacy
那麼這一個調查的過程呢本身呢事實上是比較隱秘的
This was the study concluded
Compared with an average prisoner, the convicts rated themselves as more moral
那麼這些罪犯呢他說我們比起這一個監獄裡面的一般的罪犯呢
我們呢比他們有道德
Kinder to others
More self-controlled
More law-abiding
那麼同時呢就自己本身呢能夠有自治
More compassionate
同時呢有愛心
More generous
而且呢是很慷慨
More dependable
而且可靠
More trustworthy
值得信賴
And more honest
很誠實
So each one thought that they were better than an average inmate
所以呢他們每個人都認為他比普通的一般的罪犯要好
Remarkably, they also rated themselves as higher on all these traits than an average member of the community
那值得注意的是呢他們同時還認為他們比一般在社會上的各個份子呢這些因素都要比他們還要好
With only one exception, law-abiding
都很好除了有一項
就是 law-abiding
就是在守法方面
Of course, right
那當然呢他們被關在監獄裡面了
But the prisoners rated themselves even on these traits as an average community member
So they think that they are at least equal to a community member
那麼甚至在這一方面呢他們認為他跟社會的一般的人呢是一樣的等級
They even could not admit that they were worse because they had done something bad
甚至他們不能在他自己做的錯事的方面那些事情上承認他們比別人差
Perhaps, we would like to think that we are better than these prisoners
也許我們會認為說我們肯定比這些罪犯要好
That we will be at least honest about our faults and our virtues
我們至少對於我們犯的錯或者我們個人的德行本身呢我們會誠實
But in many ways, we do the same
但是其實在很多方面呢我們做法跟他們是一樣的
We overestimate our goodness and self-justify our good qualities with minimizing the bad ones
我們經常把我們自己好的那一面呢我們高估了把我們不好的那一方面呢我們盡量就少說
This is called self-righteousness
這就叫做自益
And it is delusions of our heart
這就是我們對心的一個昏迷
Fearful, but real
可怕嗎
但是真實
That's why we need Jesus and His truth
這就是為什麼我們需要耶穌跟他的真理
But the good news is
好消息
The Lord promised to give us a new heart
神允許給我們一顆新心
By the transformation of His grace and His truth through His spirit
那麼是經過這一個神的恩典跟他的這個真理呢來轉化我們的心
So that what we need is receiving the new transformed heart
所以我們需要做的是我們要接受這一個心的轉化的心
So that our heart will be renewed and transformed
那我們的心被轉化而更新的心
So new heart begins with repentance
而新的心呢是由痛悔開始
Psalm 51.17 it says
四篇五十一篇
上帝所要的祭就是憂傷的靈
上帝啊憂傷痛悔的心你必不慶幸
Like all parts if you want to replace the new one
We must first get rid of the old
那麼就像說我們的心呢
這個機車的這個零件要更換成新
我們的心也要能夠重新轉換
It is in the presence of God knowing the true nature of our sin
唯有我們當有神的同在的時候
我們能夠真正知道我們的罪信
That there is a heart which is troubled by sin
and yet we determine to repent and to correct and to turn back to God
就是我們能夠真正知道我們的心被罪來困擾
但是我們決心要接受神的轉換
A new heart can only be given by the Lord
心心為主能夠治愈
Psalm 51.10
上帝啊求你為我做清潔的心
使我裏面重新有正直的靈
Also Ezekiel chapter 36 again 26
我也要刺給你們一個新心
將新靈放在你們裏面
又從你們的肉體中除掉石心刺給你們肉心
God promises to give our spiritual heart to all who repent
神應許我們凡痛悔的人
他要給我們一顆新的心
He will give new heart with a new spirit
and replace the heart of stone with heart of flesh
他給我們的是一顆新心同時要把我們的石心除掉
換掉一顆肉心
Ezekiel mentioned that God saves the repentant
以西捷這個書裏面說神拯救所有痛悔的人
and then God will give us His Holy Spirit
so that we can obey Him
神就會刺給我們聖靈讓我們能夠遵從祂
Jeremiah mentions that God and His people to make a new covenant
which is mentioned in Jeremiah 31
耶利米書的第31章裏面講說
祂要能夠跟祂的子民另立新約
Before His crucifixion Jesus also spoke
of a new covenant made with my blood
那麼這個新約裏面耶穌在受難以前祂說我要用我自己的血與你們另立新約
We have the Holy Communion to remember this wonderful truth
那麼我們在領聖餐的時候
我們所紀念的就是這一個真正奇妙的真理
Jesus' death make Him the mediator of this new covenant
那麼耶穌的死讓祂成為新約的中保
According to this new covenant every repentant has access to a new heart and a new spirit
Praise the Lord
那麼根據這樣的一個聖經裏面告訴我們說
我們有一個新的心能夠跟祂同在
That's why a very familiar verse we all know from 2 Corinthians chapter 5 17
若有人在基督裏他就是新做的人
舊事已過都變成新的了
Anyone is in Christ become a new creation
任何一個人只要在基督裏就是新造的
This is the newly transformed heart through grace
這是經過神的恩典讓我們一個重新轉化的一個人
So someone put it in this way grace
有人這樣子說恩典equals to grace God's riches at Christ's expense
等於神的豐盛
但是呢是加上基督的代父或者代孰
This is what we need to remember and treasure at all times as Jesus pay the price for us
這個就是我們經常要紀念我們的祖所有為我們付出的代價
The wonderful good news is our past is forgiven
有一個好消息就是我們的過去已經被赦免
And more importantly we have a new purpose of living
as this passage of 2 Corinthians chapter 5 is all about
那麼更重要的是我們知道我們在這節經文裏面告訴我們
我們有一個新的生命
We now live for Christ
我們的新的生命就是我們為主而活
And represent Him on earth to let others know about Him and His grace
而且我們代表耶穌在這個地上
能夠來讓更多的人認識祂認識祂的真理
This become our new purpose of life
So that we pursue to synchronize our heart with God's heart
這個就變成我們人生的一個新的目的
讓我們跟耶穌基督這樣的心能夠合而為一
So the new heart is filled with God's love
新的心也充滿了阻礙
Romans chapter 5 盼望不至於羞恥
因為所賜給我們的聖靈
將上帝的愛囂貫在我們心裏
With the grace of the Lord to transform our heart
The Holy Spirit fills our heart with the love of God
當我們的主的恩典充滿在我們的心的時候
我們這個時候有一個主的愛澆灌在我們的心上
If we always have the love of God fill our hearts
We will have our healthy hearts
當我們如果是經常有主的愛在我們心裏面的話
我們的心是很健康的
In this new year let us change our hearts in believing in Jesus
If you have not done so
如果我們在這個新年裏面
我請大家這個時候呢
我們願意在這個地方我們變成一個新造的人
改變我們的心
來接受耶穌基督為我們的救主
來接受耶穌基督成為我們的救主
And those who have changed their hearts and become Christian already
Keep our heart healthy
如果我們已經改變了我們的心
這時候我們要把我們的心保持健康的狀態
To fill with the love of God, not the heart of stone, but the heart of flesh
我們看到神他把我們的心從實心變成肉心
And love from God is the power to change
那麼神的愛就是一個改變的能量
President Jimmy Carter said he was greatly inspired by someone who told his own secret of success
那麼這個卡特總統呢,他說他呢
有一次被一個人他分享他自己的成功的秘訣的時候呢
他受到激勵
And finally, the simple yet profound theology
那麼在這個過程中間呢
他領會到一個簡單但是呢
能夠振奮人心的一個神學
The person told him, Mr. Carter, we only need to have two loves in our lives
那麼這個人告訴卡特總統說我們一個人只需要兩種愛在我們的心裡面
Love for God
愛神
And love for the person who appears to be in front of us at any time
另外一種就是那種當我們面對任何站在我們面前的人
我們愛他的這樣的一個愛
President Jimmy Carter found it most profound and inspired to him
那麼卡特總統覺得這一番話是非常振奮他的心的一件事情
There are many times in life when we are disappointed or frustrated
很多時候我們的心失望、挫折
Or anger or bitter
說是憤怒甚至痛苦
But we can choose not to have bitter hearts
但是我們可以選擇不要有一個苦主的心
And ask the Holy Spirit fills our heart with God's love and His kindness
求神能夠用祂的愛跟祂的恩慈來充滿我們
The opposite of a wicked heart is the heart of kindness and mercy
那麼一個邪惡的心的反面就是神
就是一個帶著愛跟憐憫的心
Which is the proper result of the transformation of grace
這就是一個恩典轉換的一個正當的結果
So Ephesians chapter 4 32 並要以恩慈相待全聯盟的心
Francis Shaver, a famous American theologian and pastor of the 20th century said
所以 Frank Shaver 他是一個很著名的神學家
同時是二十世紀的一位牧者
He said true Christian life lies in inner conditions not in outward appearance
他說一個真實的基督徒的生命是在他裡面而不是表現出來的
And true Christian life consists of true love for God and love for others from within
那麼真正的一個真的基督徒他的一個行為是要愛神而且愛別人而且是發自於內心的
The new heart is filled with God's word
心心充滿主道
Colossians chapter 3 16 當用各樣的智慧把基督的道理豐豐富富地存在心裡
用詩章 頌詞 靈歌 彼此教導 互相勸誡 心被恩感 歌頌上帝
God loves us and desire the very best for you and me
神愛我們 他要讓我們你跟我得到最好的
That's why he gave us his word, his holy word
也因此他把他自己的話語賜給我們
So that when we dwell in it and walk out of it, we will know the truth and be set free
如果我們與他同行 在他這個中間來行走的話
So we will be set free
我們就會得到自由
Free from fear
沒有恐懼的自由
Free from delusion
沒有昏迷的自由
Free from temptation
沒有誘惑的自由
Free from sin
沒有犯罪的自由
God's grace and his truth work hand in hand together
to provide us with true joy and freedom
那麼這是神的愛跟神的這樣的一個恩典
是互相效力 讓我們能夠有一個喜悅的心
Your thoughts and your hearts will either conform to the world
我們的思想要不就來跟這個世界認同
Or they will be transformed by the word of God as we walk through the faith
或者說我們在信心中行的時候
我們就接受被神來轉化我們的心
All too often we are so overwhelmed by technology
our personal dramas or our earnest ambitions
that we neglect the importance of the word of God
我們經常 我們一個人常常傾向於
我們被一些科技跟各種世上的價值觀
我們自己的地位在這些事情中間來影響了我們
The wisdom is to know about the word of God
and put it in our heart
so that we will be dwell in the word of God
那麼真正我們在這個地方
我們所學到的是說
我們要在神的話語中間
我們能夠得到造就
and the Holy Spirit, the Spirit of Truth
will help us to understand the Bible
and to have a wonderful and victorious life
是聖靈還有祂的恩典
讓我們能夠了解神的話語
能夠幫助我們日常所思所行
It's another new year
我們又來到一個新的年度
We ask the Lord to renew our spiritual life
我們求主來更新我們的生命
More prayer
so the Holy Spirit will prompt to us
那這個聖靈能夠來到我們中間
More Bible reading, more worshiping
多讀經 禱告
Once again, we encourage each other
as the new year started
we strive for the very best
我要鼓勵各位在新的這一年中間
我們繼續努力
能夠真正的一天比一天更好
If you feel boring or plateauing
someone suggested consider trying a new Bible translation maybe
so that you have a new perspective on the Bible
如果你有時候你覺得你自己好像心煩了
或者你好像碰到瓶頸了
那這個時候我們可以怎麼樣呢
我們可以也許用個聖經的新譯本
讓我們對神的話語有一些新的認識
甚至能夠看一些聖經的軟件
或者說一些錄音檔案
或者我們每天早上可以藉著詩篇
我們一起來禱告
Consider involving a friend
也許我們可以邀請朋友
也許我們可以用一些讀經指南
能夠幫助我們在聖經方面
有一些更多的興趣
最重要的是讓神的話語
充滿了我們的心
神祂的渴望是讓我們每一個人
我們尋求祂的話語
能夠了解祂
應用在我們自己的生命
那我們這樣子就可以為基督耶穌而活
祂這地方說我們要歌頌神
然後心倍恩感
那麼所以前面那一句也是這樣講
所以跟下來我們就講到心的心
是要充滿了感恩
So what's the preface verse
3.15
又要叫基督的平安
在你們心裡作主
你們也為此夢召歸為一體
且要傳感謝的心
When your heart is full of gratitude
your heart will be guided by the peace of Christ
讓我們的心充滿了感恩
讓我們的心被基督的平安來引領我們
You will not easily prone to jealousy, pride, depression, or bitterness
這樣子的話我們就不至於經常
落入這樣的一個真正的驕傲或者沮喪跟嫉妒裡面
Have you noticed that unthankful persons are never happy?
不知道有沒有大家注意到說一個不知道感恩的人
他們永遠不快樂
It all started with an attitude or the heart thing
這都是一個心態的問題
這是一個心裡面的問題
If you want to have a happy marriage
and a good relationship with others
如果你要有一個快樂的婚姻
或者跟別人有好的關係
Be thankful
你要感恩
就是靠著感恩
要靠著感恩
As researchers find out the key to a happy and lasting marriage
might be as simple as a regular expressing gratitude
那麼所以研究說呢
你如果說要快樂的話
這一個真正的核心呢
就是你經常要說出的感恩
Be thankful to your spouse
要謝謝你的配偶
Your kids
孩子
Your parents
你的父母
Your brothers and sisters in church
教會的弟兄姐妹們
Express and let them know that you appreciate them
要話說出來說你謝謝他們
Nothing builds up people like encouragement
沒有任何一件事情
能夠比這個鼓勵人更能夠建造人
And then we can have the peace of Christ rule in our hearts
讓我們有這一個基督的平安在我們裡面來做主
So now we understand the nature of our human heart
我們現在我們知道這個人心的這個本性
And by God's grace because of Christ
We can receive a newly transformed heart from Him
那麼就是因為神的這個恩典
讓我們能夠重新接受一個新的心
Not long ago I read a book
That was a gift for my daughter as a Christmas gift
那麼我不久以前我女兒的一個聖誕禮物
送給我一本書
And if your daughter gave you a gift
You better read it, right?
記住啊
如果女兒給你一本書你最好要讀它
It was penned by Dr. Henry Cloud
Titled "Changes that Heal"
那麼這本書的作者是Henry Cloud
他的書名呢是說
"改變得到醫治"
When we change according to God's will
We get healed
當我們根據神的心意改變的時候
我們就得到醫治
The book's core idea is to help us to set boundaries
In our hearts and in our lives
Based on the wisdom from Proverbs chapter 423
那麼這本書裡面呢
它大概的意思就是說
讓我們要根據真言的4章23節
能夠得到那個智慧來改變我們
So set boundaries in our hearts
那就是說要設立我們個人的一個界線
So what's Proverbs chapter 423? Do you know?
那麼這個真言4章23節說什麼呢
So the Bible said
Above all else, guard your hearts, for everything you do flows from it
所以你們要保守你的心
勝過保守一切
因為凡事都是由心裡面發出來的
It helps people, the book, helps people to understand about
What is real and what is ideal
那麼能夠這樣子的話
我們能夠幫助我們了解什麼是真實的
什麼是理想的
Which I can also apply the same here
as the old heart, the sinful nature
because of the fall of the humankind
那麼也可以應用到今天我講到這一個舊的心
是因為人類墮落以後的一個罪的本性
That is real, 這是真的
and also the new heart which God give us through Christ
and His grace, that is ideal
那麼那個理想的那一部分呢
是因為我們接受了神的恩典
有了這一個心的改變心
and our entire life's path
depends on how healthy our heart is
那麼我們這一生的過程
其實就靠著我們到底心的健康狀態
For Christians especially
特別對基督徒
The inherent problem in the relationship
between the ideal and the real
那麼關於真實跟理想
這中間所存在的一個實質的問題
It's sometimes that the ideal
judges the real as unacceptable
and brings down condemnation which hurts
那麼這個問題在什麼呢
就是說理想經常否定了這一個真實
同時呢在這個過程中間呢
因為否定它就定罪它
讓這個對方痛苦
我們自己痛苦
It can be from our perfectionism
也許說我們是一個完美主義
or lack of understanding about
the reality of our sinful nature
as described in the Bible
或者我們對於聖經所講的
人的罪性本身我們認識不對
or other wrong concepts from the world
或者這個世界上給我們的
各種不同的概念
even from our own family of origin
甚至跟我們的原生家庭有關係
The problems go on when we deny the bad
and have a delusion about how good we are
所以我們是怎麼樣呢
我們否定這個我們自己的不好不是
那麼在這個裡面就有一顆昏迷的心
錯覺的心
Or on the other hand deny the good
and decide there is no ideal standard to live up
不但這樣子我們否定那些好的
那麼認為說我永遠做不到
So that we become complacent
所以我們在這個地方
我們就給自己藉口
This further result in judging
and attacking ourselves
那麼這個結果就是我們來攻擊
同時定罪我們自己
And judging and attacking others
也定罪別人
Or making us further depart
from God's purpose for our lives
那這只有讓神為我們所定的
一個人的目標裡面越來越遠離
Therefore we should understand from the Bible
and from God's perspective
to accept both the real
所以我們必須從聖經的角度
跟神的一個眼光來接受兩者
就第一個是真實
To God against it
那麼同時我們要抵抗它
And to pursue the ideal
through His grace and truth
同時我們要去追求
理想的那一部分
We accept and forgive the bad
both of ourselves and others
through the grace which Christ offers
經由基督的恩典
我們用這樣的一個方式
我們要接受這個不好的部分
As we stand in grace
we accept the bad and the good in ourselves
and we will be able to accept them in others
那麼我們站在一個恩典的基礎上
我們接受不但是好的也有不好的
But at the same time
we are clinging to the ideal as a goal
但是我們同時要把這個理想
當成我們生命的一個目標
That we strive for now
on the basis of full acceptance from God
and the knowledge of His truth
那麼我們在神的這樣的一個
完全接納我們跟祂的真理的基礎上
我們去追求日日追求
This transformation or change
brings healing to ourselves
to our relationship with God
and with others
這就是轉化
轉化我們跟自己跟別人的
這樣的一個新的轉化的一個新的關係
That brings healing
可以因此就帶來的就是一個醫治
To start a new year
we may resolve to bring some changes
so that we can live more healthier
新的一年開始
我們這個時候可以來做一個決定
就是讓我們有一個新的改變的心
Maybe do more exercise, eat right, etc. right?
那麼也許我們可以多運動各方面
Do you have one?
你有沒有一個新的新年新計畫呢?
To get more healthy
讓我們更健康
But I pray and seek God for every one of us
Our families, our church
and each of our individual
我個人的禱告就是說
我要真正在尋求神的過程中間
能夠真正讓我的家
我的教會能夠更好
And every individual in our church
還有我們教會裡面的每一位會員
Can be further transformed to have a more healthy heart
讓我們每一個人都因此這樣子
都被轉換有一個更健康的一個心
Because everything we do flows from it
因為所有的事都是由心發出
The new heart is given by God
我們的新的心是神所賦予的
Only by His grace through Christ
唯有經過基督跟祂的恩典
But above all else as the Bible said
但是聖經裡面說的最重要的
We are also guarding our hearts
Through the new spirit, the spirit of truth
我們要藉著這樣的一個心
來保守我們的心
That God gives us
So that our hearts will be more
Filled with God's love
充滿了主愛
And filled with His kindness
充滿了恩慈
Filled with God's word
充滿了主道
And filled with gratitude
充滿了感恩
And also to fill with the peace of Christ
充滿了和平
May God bless our church
願神祝福我們教會
And every one of us
以及我們每一位
In the coming year
To be a better witness for Him
能夠在這個新的一年
成為基督更好的一個見證人
To have a better ministry
讓我們的侍公更好
And live a better life for His glory
讓我們能夠活出一個
更榮耀祂的一個生命
But everything start from our heart
凡事是重新開始
So let God help us
Repent from sin
讓我們求神幫助我們
讓我們有個痛悔的一個心
And seek His help
尋求祂的幫助
Ask the Holy Spirit to fill us
求聖靈充滿我們
Transform our heart
轉化我們的心
So that we have a newly
Transformed heart through grace
能夠在恩典中間
我們領受一個
新的轉化的心
And His truth
他的真理
And His love
以及他的愛
Let's pray together
讓我們一起禱告
Our Father in heaven
Thank you so much
For your wonderful word
阿爸天父
謝謝你奇妙的話語
And thank you so much
For loving us
Even though we do not know you
謝謝你
在我們還不認識你的時候
就愛我們
Because of Christ
We receive the grace from you
因為基督的緣故
我們領受你的恩典
And we ask that
You will transform our heart
我們求你能夠
轉化我們的心
So on one hand
We know our sinful nature
一方面我們了解
我們的罪性
We need to guard against it
我們能夠真正抵抗它
Guard against it
So that the pride
The evil
And also the delusion
Will not hinder us
那這一些驕傲
這些邪惡
這些昏迷
不在我們裡面
And because of your grace
And your forgiveness
We have hope
就是因為你的恩典
跟你的饒恕
And we thank God
For a new heart from you
謝謝你賜給我們一顆新星
So that our heart
Will become more like you
讓我們更像你的一顆新星
And filled with your love
能夠被你的愛來浇灌
So that we express our love to you
And to whoever in front of us
At any time
我們能夠隨時
能夠真正地
向你表達我們的愛
跟出現在我們面前的每一個人
向他表達愛
We express our kindness
把我們的恩恥
And fill your heart with your truth
Through your word
讓我們的心
充滿在你自己的話語的教導
So that we live our life
Full of gratitude
讓我們活出一個
充滿感恩的一個生活
And fill with the peace of Christ
能夠真正有基督的平安
May you bless everybody of our church
求你保守我們每一位教會的弟兄姊妹
Our dear brothers and sisters that we love
我們所愛的弟兄姊妹們
May you transform once again
願大家都能夠
在這個地方被轉化
So that our heart will be more healthier
讓我們的心
一天比一天健康
And our church will be more healthier
教會也更健康
And your glory will be shown
你的榮耀要被彰顯
And people will know that we are Christians in your love
人能夠看出我們就是基督徒
In the name of our Lord Jesus Christ we pray, Amen
我們將禱告奉耶穌基督的聖名
Amen